Guide to the Kurt Akeley Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Kurt Akeley papers
1982-2000
SC0628
Akeley, Kurt
22.5 Linear feet (15 boxes) and 550 megabytes
Papers of Kurt Akeley largely pertaining to research and product development for Silicon Graphics Inc.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Kurt Akeley, 2001
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biography
Kurt Akeley, one of the founders of Silicon Graphics, Incorporated, earned his M.S.E.E. from Stanford University in 1982. He has published papers on computer graphics architectures and taught courses on graphics programming at the annual SIGGRAPH conferences.
Scope and Content
This collection includes memoranda, reports, manuals, publications, notebooks, outlines and text for presentations, email printouts, patents, slides, and videos pertaining to research and product development for Silicon Graphics and its customers; collection also includes Akeley's notes from a class with Jim Clark, 1987.
Access Terms
Clark, Jim.; Silicon Graphics Inc.; Computer assisted graphics.; Computer graphics.; Visual programming (Computer science).
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - ALIAS (Animation) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AMOCO, Jan 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chrysler (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - C-Cube Microsystems (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - CIE (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dassault Systems (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - D.H. Brown (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - D.H. Brown (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - DUPONT (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - EDS (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Evans & Sutherland (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ford (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Electric (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Georgia Tech (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - ID Software (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ILM (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Intergraph (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - KAPL (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Kodak (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Kubota (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Landmark (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lattice Technology (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Mallincicrodt Radiology (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Marconi (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Matra (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - McDonnall Douglas (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Multigen (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - NASA (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - NASA Langley (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - NTT (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Phillips Medical (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Quality Research (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Raytheon (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Sarnoff Research (David Zeltzer) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Schlumberger (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - SDRC (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Sense 8 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - TEXACO (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Microsoft Graphics Presentation, April 1991 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - SE Meeting, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - National Academy of Science Presentation, Feb. 1993 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Engineering Forum Graphics Presentation, Jan. 1993 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Performer Slides (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - VRML Slides (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - ImageVision Slides (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - IRIS GL 5.0 (Early Open GL) (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Open GL Misc Slides (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Developer Forum '92 Open GL Presentation (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - GLX Presentation, Jan. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - EuroGraphics Hardware Workshop Presentation, Sept. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - SigGraph '92 Open GL Course Intro Slides, June 1992 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - SE Presentation 94-95? Stanford Presentation 8-24-95 PEX Group Presentation 92ish (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Waves Presentation John Mashey (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Analyst Presentation LINUX, May 1999 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - SE Broadcast 320/540 Intro, Nov. 1998 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - SLINX Presentation, Nov. 1998 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Analyst Briefing, July 1998 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - We Have A Problem New Plans Pitch, July 1998 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Darpa Visit Graphics as Compression, July 1998 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - European Sales Conference, July 1998 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - The New SGI Rick Belluzzo, June 1998 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Americas Sales Conference, April 1998 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - WINHEC, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Cinequest Maverick Award, Jan. 30, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Graphics API Roadmap EuroForum '98, Jan. 1998 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - EuroForum 98 Keynote, Jan. 1998 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Fahrenheit Announcement Inside SGI, Dec. 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Graphics Basics Sales Meeting, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - SigGraph Open GL Paper, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - SigGraph Panel Research Topics, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Financial Analysts Presentation, Sept. 5, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Limits Presentation Mitre Corp/Mashey, April 1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - China Trip, April 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Microsoft Meeting NT Plans, Mar. 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Culture & Organization Exec Offsite, Mar. 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Leadership Forum Strategic API Talk, Feb. 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Values Slides (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Kodak Presentation, Dec. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - ETC Presentation, Dec. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Presentation to Ed GFX Plans, Oct. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - NSF Graphics Future Presentation, Aug. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - SigGraph '96 Panel Presentation Imaging Features (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - SigGraph '96 Panel Presentation GFX PCs vs. Workstations (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - ASD Open GL Presentation Mid '96 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Developer Forum 96 Presentation, Mar. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - PRS Presentation SFT vs. HRD, Oct. 1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - EuroGraphics Hardware Workshop Presentations, Sept. 1995 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Open GL 1.1 Slides SigGraph, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - SigGraph Award Slides, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - IEEE Presentation, Summer 1995 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Stanford Presentation on INF Reality, May 1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Japan Expo 94 Slides, Oct. 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Power Challenge Slides, Aug. 1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - SE Meeting, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - VSG Presentation, Jan. 1994 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - SigGraph '93 open GL Course Presentation, July 1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Patent Office Presentation, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Patent Office Presentation, July 1993 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - SigGraph '93 Reality Engine Slides (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - SigGraph, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - AutoFact, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - NAS, NRC Virtual Reality (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - SigGraph, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - SigGraph, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - SigGraph, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - SigGraph, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - SigGraph, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - SigGraph, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - SigGraph, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - SigGraph, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Euro Hdwr Wrk, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Euro Hdwr Wrk '95 (empty) (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Eurographics, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - HotChips, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Graphicon, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Graphicon, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - I/TES, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - SE meeting '97 San Diego (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dev Forum [Developer's Forum], 1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dev Forum, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dev Forum, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dev Forum, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Euro Dev Forum, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - EuroForum, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Tech Forum '99 Keynote (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - IEEE, Oct. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - GL Book (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Open GL (very early) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Early Open GL Notes (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Open GL (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - ARB [Architectural Review Board], June 1994 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - ARB, Aug. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - ARB, Dec. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - ARB, Feb. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - ARB, May 1995 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - ARB, Sept. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - ARB, Dec. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - ARB, Feb. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - ARB, May 1996 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - ARB, Aug. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - ARB, Dec. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - ARB, Feb. 1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - ARB, May 1997 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - ARB, Mar. 1998 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - ARB (London), June 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ARB, Sept. 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ARB, Dec. 1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - ARB, Mar. 1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - ARB, Sept. 1999 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - ARB, Dec. 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - ARB, Mar. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - SketchPad Script (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Graphics Strategy (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Compressed Depth Buf (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Open GL 1.1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Open GL 1.1 Spec 28 Sept '95 (empty) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Open GL FFT (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Sun Open GL (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Microsoft Open GL (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - NURBS (early) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - IBM GL (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - XIL (Sun Imaging) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - E and S Open GL (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Intel 3D-R (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Dore (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Subdivision Surfaces (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - GLC (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - GLR (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - GLUT (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Graphics Papers (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Graphics Papers (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Graphics Papers (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Graphics Papers (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Press Tour, Dec. 1995 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Power Series & GFX Libraries (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Power Challenge & Power Onyx (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Cali/Dali, Summer 1999 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Origin & Onyx 3000 Announcement Materials (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Iris Indigo Intro (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Origin & Onyx 2 & O2 Intro (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bali (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Kona (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Venice (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Venice (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - IMP 5 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - VGX (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Kubota Denali GFX System (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Pixel Flow (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - HP Volume Render (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Open GL Vision Tour, May 1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Randy Nickel (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Matt Eldridge Pomegranate Graphics (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Robert Dewar Adacore (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Pat Hanrahan (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Randi Rost (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Eric Chen (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Gary Demos (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Patent 5,051,737 Clipping Polygons (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Patent 5,193,145 Quad Decomp (empty) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Patent 5,230,039 Texture Range (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Patent 5,266,941 Stencil (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Patent 5,343,558 VGX Scan Conversion (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Patent 5,347,618 Bevel Planes (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Patent 5,369,739 Remask Generation (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Patent 5,394,170 Stencil 2 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Patent 5,819,017 Selectively Storing Depth Information of a 3D Image (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Patent 5,854,631 Fragment Merge (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Patent 5,933,155 Cushion Buffer (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Silhouette Patent (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Patent Multisample Dither (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Trade Secrets Program (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - IP Value - LECG (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Fog & Lighting (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - CSG (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Stereo (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - PDN's (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Pixar (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - G Graphics Library Allen Akin (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gamma (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Phigs Plus (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Audio & Video (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Visual Simulation (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Volume Rendering (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Texture Mapping (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 3D Com, Inc. "True" 3D (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Clipping (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Triangle Strips (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Silhouettes (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - The SGI 4D/240 GTX SuperWorkStation (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Hidden Charms of Z-Buffer (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Stencil Article (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - SGI Historical Documents (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 360-Degree Feedback (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Spirit Trip, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Software Summit (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Spirit (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - SigGraph 2000 Meetings (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Tech Forum, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Horizon (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Ergonomics (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - SGI Logo (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Old OrgCharts (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Global Partners (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Octel (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Tech Talk (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - SGI 2000 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Fitness for Life Don Nava (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Scenarios (NT, MP) (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - CDP Business Plan (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Inspector (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Open GL Optimizer (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - SGI Suppliers (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Environment (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - WPD Plan, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Hiring (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Cosmo (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Etc (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Leadership Forum, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Donations Committee (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Management (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Lego/Kego (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Exec Offsites (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Exec Offsites, Sept. 1996 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Exec Offsite, Dec. 1996 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Exec Offsite, May 1997 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - SSG Offsite, Jan. 1997 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Multimedia Asia '96 Malaysia (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Safety (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Atlantis Graphics (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Outside Help (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - About SGI (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Univ of Delaware (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - U of D Indy Labs (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Polo Shirts (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Nintendo 64 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - PCB/GEM (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - BPC, (Summer 1981) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - IM1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - DA2/DA3 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - DC4 (CAE Timing) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - IP2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - PM2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - IP1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Clover 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - UC4 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - UC5 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - DA1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - GT Chip Set (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Eclipse (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - C2 Raster (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Clover 2 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - GE4 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Clover 3 CPU (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Boston Eng Notes (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Boston Presentation (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Boston Misc (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - GE 11 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Po's (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Logic Devices (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Shared Resources (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Twin Industries WWM Wirewrap (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Vitesse (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - WaferScale (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Weitek (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Xilinx (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - LSI Logic (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Terminals (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Unix Commands (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Unix Documents (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Data Sheets (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - ViewGraphs (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - My Code (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - UNC (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Other Graphics Products (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Other Graphics Products (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Phone (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Customer Visits (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Graphics Class Jim Clark, Feb. 1987 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Transmission Line Theory (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - RS-232 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Cache Papers (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Benchmarks (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - ASD Vision (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - SGI 2000, 1 binder(s) (Box 9)
  - Human Factors, 1 binder(s) (Box 9)
  - Clover 1, 1 binder(s) (Box 9)
  - Clover GL, 1 binder(s) (Box 9)
  - Transparencies and Slides, 3 binder(s) (Box 9)
  - BPC 2 Alpha, 1 binder(s) (Box 10)
  - Iris GT Chip Set Specifications (Box 10)
  - Iris 4-D Series Documentation, 2 binder(s) (Box 10)
  - Graphica Obscura, 1 binder(s) (Box 10)
  - Iris Fast Facts (Box 10)
  - Unix System V Documentation (Box 10)
  - Corporate Telephone Directory (Box 10)
  - Iris Guides (2) (Box 10)
  - RenderMan Interface (Box 10)
  - Cosmo 3D Spec (Box 10)
  - Iris Performer Reference Pages (Box 10)
  - Iris Performer Programming Guide (Box 10)
  - SGI Pipeline, Nov/Dec 1990 vol. 1 #6-1992 Year End vol. 3 #6 (Box 11)
  - Developer News, May/June 1994-2nd Quarter 2000 (Box 11)
  - Kurt Akeley Notebooks, 1982-2000; 17 volume(s) (Box 11)
  - SGI Annual Reports, 1987-1998, 2000 (Box 12)
  - Portfolio Snapshots (Box 12)
  - Developer News, Feb 1995-August 1995 (Box 12)
  - IRIS Universe #1-#27 (Box 12)
  - Misc Publications (Box 12)
  - Unix Manuals (5) (Box 13)
  - SGI Training Manual (Box 13)
  - Software Design, 1995 (Box 13)
  - Video Tex, 1991; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Cosmo Software Suite Pathway to the Second Web, 1997; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Onyx InfiniteReality Demo Tape V.4, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Memory-Based Graphics, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Venice Demos, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Bite TV, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Iris 4-D Series Documentation, 6 binder(s) (Box 14)
  - Iris 4-D Series Documentation, 9 binder(s) (Box 15)
  - Poster: IRIS 6.5 SGI gallery of modern art
  - Poster: Virtual Surgery / Virtual Successes
- Computer files, Accession ARCH-2004-301
  Memoranda, reports, source code, text, and slides from presentations pertaining to research and product development for Silicon Graphics Inc. Includes text files, Showcase files, and PostScript versions of the Showcase files.
  - postscript_versions
  - Stanford#2
  - Stanford#3